ANANDH

ELECTRICAL ENGINEER

PHONE I (+91) 7708554990

EMAIL I anandhvepl@gmail.com

LOCATION I Chennai, INDIA

EXPERIENCE I 10 Years 0 Month

Key Skills

- Control Panel Design
- Secondary
- Motors
- LT
- VCBS
- Commissioning
- Switchgear
- Control Panel
- Electrical CAD
- AutoCAD
- Cable Schedule
- Cable Tray
- Cable Laying
- Cable Testing
- VFDS
- PLC Panel
- MCC

Certification

Bachelor Of Engineering

Languages

Profile Summary

I have a good working knowledge of LT (415v) panels, control and relay panels scheme checks. Development of Single line and three line diagram in AutoCAD. Switchgear selection, Panel design & complete wiring drawing. Preparation of electrical drawings detail (General arrangement, SLD, wiring, BOQ, Calculations). Worked on Siemens VFDs (SINAMICS V20, G120). Basic Knowledge of PLC (Rockwell Automation, Siemens). Basic knowledge on Rockwell Automation PLC (Micro Logix, Compact Logix and Control Logix). Basic knowledge on Siemens P LC (S7-300, S7-400, S7-1200, S7-1500) Ability to develop functional and detailed design documents from P&ID???s process description and existing automation design developments. Good knowledge in designing of LV panel MCC, Relay panel, UPS, Battery, Distribution boards from initial stage to panel delivery.

Work Experience

Electrical Engineer

Utility Projects and Services private Limited (UPSPL)

11/2021 - 06/2022

- 1. Shift manpower handling & manpower allocation for Planned Maintenance activities.
- 2. Maintenance shift activities follow up and handling of break down. 3. Planning and exaction of Regular Maintenance activities. 4. Work allocation to subordinates and monitoring their activities. 5. Monitoring of maintenance spares and inventories. 6. Spares indent follow-up / interaction with Purchase

- Tamil
- Hindi
- English

Social links

 www.linkedin.com/in/anand h-thangavel-8b1833174 Team. 7. Utility operation and its Consumption monitoring. 8. AMC activity follow up and monitoring. 9. Preventive Maintenance (TBM) Planning & execution. 10. Predictive Maintenance (CBM) activity planning & execution. 11. Red Tag completion activities.

Electrical Engineer

Voltech Engineers Private Limited 10/2018 - 08/2021

1. Preparation of electrical drawing detailly (General arrangement, SLD, Schematic drawings, Bill of materials, technical calculations, Cable schedule and Terminal drawing) 2. Electrical design for LV/MV control panels types MCC (ABB, SIEMENS, SCHNEIDER and L&T), Soft Starter, Capacitor banks, Relay Panels, UPS, battery panels, distribution boards and all type of switchgears. 3. Single line diagram preparation, three-line diagram and general arrangement drawing preparation in 2D. 4. Cross Verification of all designs as per UL, IEC standard & followed its safety regulations. 5. Testing of panels as per electrical scheme and scope. 6. Commissioning support for MCC and VFD panels. 7. Worked on Siemens VFDs (SINAMICS V20, G120) 8. Basic Knowledge of PLC (Rockwell Automation, Siemens) 9. Basic knowledge on Rockwell Automation PLC (Micro Logix, Compact Logix and Control Logix) 10. Basic knowledge on Siemens PLC (\$7-300, \$7-400, \$7-1200, \$7-1500) 11. Ability to test, troubleshoot electrical panels. 12. Ability to carry out engineering aspects like preparation of As-build scheme, sizing calculation of transformers, feeders, cables as per international standards. 13. Good knowledge in designing of LV panel MCC, Relay panel, UPS, Battery, Distribution boards from initial stage to panel delivery.

Senior Commissioning Engineer- II
DIGITAL ENERGY ENGINEERING SERVICES
WLL
09/2017 - 09/2018

1. Preparation of electrical drawing detailly

(General arrangement, SLD, Schematic drawings, Bill of materials, technical calculations, Cable schedule and Terminal drawing) 2. Electrical design for LV/MV control panels types MCC (ABB, SIEMENS, SCHNEIDER and L&T), Soft Starter, Capacitor banks, Relay Panels, UPS, battery panels, distribution boards and all type of switchgears. 3. Single line diagram preparation, three-line diagram and general arrangement drawing preparation in 2D. 4. Cross Verification of all designs as per UL, IEC standard & followed its safety regulations. 5. Testing of panels as per electrical scheme and scope. 6. Commissioning support for MCC and VFD panels. 7. Worked on Siemens VFDs (SINAMICS V20, G120) 8. Basic Knowledge of PLC (Rockwell Automation, Siemens) 9. Basic knowledge on Rockwell Automation PLC (Micro Logix, Compact Logix and Control Logix) 10. Basic knowledge on Siemens PLC (\$7-300, \$7-400, \$7-1200, \$7-1500) 11. Ability to test, troubleshoot electrical panels. 12. Ability to carry out engineering aspects like preparation of As-build scheme, sizing calculation of transformers, feeders, cables as per international standards. 13. Good knowledge in designing of LV panel MCC, Relay panel, UPS, Battery, Distribution boards from initial stage to panel delivery.

Senior Commissioning Engineer - II Voltech Engineers Pvt Ltd 11/2014 - 09/2017

1. Preparation of electrical drawing detailly (General arrangement, SLD, Schematic drawings, Bill of materials, technical calculations, Cable schedule and Terminal drawing) 2. Electrical design for LV/MV control panels types MCC (ABB, SIEMENS, SCHNEIDER and L&T), Soft Starter, Capacitor banks, Relay Panels, UPS, battery panels, distribution boards and all type of switchgears.

3. Single line diagram preparation, three-line diagram and general arrangement drawing preparation in 2D. 4. Cross Verification of all designs as per UL, IEC standard & followed its safety regulations. 5. Testing of panels as per electrical scheme and scope. 6.

Commissioning support for MCC and VFD panels. 7. Worked on Siemens VFDs (SINAMICS V20, G120) 8. Basic Knowledge of PLC (Rockwell Automation, Siemens) 9. Basic knowledge on Rockwell Automation PLC (Micro Logix, Compact Logix and Control Logix) 10. Basic knowledge on Siemens PLC (\$7-300, \$7-400, \$7-1200, \$7-1500) 11. Ability to test, troubleshoot electrical panels. 12. Ability to carry out engineering aspects like preparation of As-build scheme, sizing calculation of transformers, feeders, cables as per international standards. 13. Good knowledge in designing of LV panel MCC, Relay panel, UPS, Battery, Distribution boards from initial stage to panel delivery.

Electrical Site Engineer
Golden Construction
08/2013 - 08/2014

1. Planning and execution of site work & Coordination with Customer for execution related matter. 2. Ability to read electrical drawings. 3. Key Line diagram (Protection SLD) 4. Wiring diagrams 5. Panel General Arrangement & BOQ 6. Interface drawings 7. AC/DC Auxiliary schematics

Education

B.Tech/B.E. - Electrical 2013 Anna University

Grade - Pass

12th 2009

> Tamil Nadu , Tamil Grade - 80-84.9%

10th 2007

> Tamil Nadu , Tamil Grade - 75-79.9%

Projects

Project: Lower Fars Heavy Oil Development Program Phase-1 33kV/440V Substation 122 Days

Site visit & data collection from customer for load list & instrument list. Detailed electrical drawing preparation as per Standard using AutoCAD. Technical Calculation& switchgears selections data sheet submittal. Testing of panels as per IEC standard activity. Preparation of field cable schedule. Preparation of testing procedure for all panels, document controlling. Commissioning support for all electrical panels(MCC, PLC, VFD, UPS)